# **MAHBUBUR RAHMAN**

mahbuburahman.github.io | mahabub708@gmail.com | Linkedin

#### **OVERVIEW**

I am a senior software product manager at Crowdbotics (low code/no code platform). My research interest is designing large-scale intelligent software systems, finding patterns, and reusing them.

In terms of software products, I am interested in designing AI-driven components that can help individuals and communities solve their problems. Through applying various analytical tools and meticulously designed algorithms, I would like to expand my expertise by incorporating my skills into academic and industrial projects with practical applications.

### **EDUCATION**

# EASTERN UNIVERSITY, DHAKA, BANGLADESH

September 2015-May 2019

Bachelor in Computer Science & Engineering GPA: 3.01/4.0

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **CROWDBOTICS**

Barkley, CA(USA)

Senior Software Product Manager

April 2020–Present (Remote)

- Led successful integration of gRPC based complex backend APIs and lead the entire development team.
- Third-part REST API integration with different services
- Design software roadmap with different tools and visualize them in grantt chart
- Lead a small team of software engineers, designers & QA
- Work with software architect to find the best solution for different mobile app technology

# **BACKBONE OFFICES**

Abbotsford, BC(Canada)

Junior software engineer

June 2017-March 2020(Remote)

- Maintain and develop website for co-working space, integrate 3rd party APIs for booking space
- Configure Cisco Meraki based network system
- Research different market and visualize data

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Javascript, R, C, C++, Java, PHP
- Markup Languages: CSS, HTML
- Database: MySql, Oracle, MongoDB
- ML Framework: PyTorch, Tensorflow

• Web Framework: Django, Flask, Laravel, React

• Visualization Tool: D3.js

• VCS: Git

• Image Analysis Tools: OpenCV, Dlib

• PRC & API: gRPC & RestAPI